chapter 7even of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna Su chapter 7 Ginger One day when Ginger and I were
standing alone in the shade, we had a great deal of talk; she wanted to know
all about my bringing up and breaking in, and I told
her. “Well,” said she, “if I had had your bringing up I might have had as good a
temper as you, but now I don't believe I ever
shall.” “Why not?” I said. “Because it has all been so different with me,” she replied. “I
never had anyone horse or man, that was kind to me, or that I cared to please, for
in the first place I was taken from my mother as soon as I was weaned, and put
in with a lot of other young Cults none of them cared for me, and I cared for
none of them. There was no kind master like yours to look after me, and talk to
me, and bring me nice things to eat. The man that had the care of us never gave
me a kind word in my life. I do not mean
that he ill used me, but he did not care
for us one bit further than to see that we had plenty to eat, and shelter in the
winter. A footpath ran through our field, and very often the great boys passing
through would fling stones to make us gallop. I was never hit, but one fine
young cult was badly cut in the face, and I should think it would be a scar for
life. We did not care for them, but of course it made us more wild, and we
settled it in our minds that boys were our enemies. We had very good fun in the free
meadows, galloping up and down and chasing each other round and round the
field; then standing still under the shade of the trees. But when it came to
breaking in, that was a bad time for me; several men came to catch me, and when at
last they closed me in at one corner of the field, one caught me by the for loock
another caught me by the nose and held it so tight I could hardly draw my
breath; then another took my under jaar in his hard hand and wrenched my mouth
open, and so by force they got on the halter and the bar into my mouth; then
one dragged me along by the halter, another flogging behind, and this was the
first experience I had of men's kindness; it was all force. They did not give me a
chance to know what they wanted. I was high bred and had a great deal of spirit,
and was very wild, no doubt, and gave them, I dare say, plenty of trouble, but then it
was dreadful to be shut up in the a stall day after day instead of having my
liberty, and I Fred and pined and wanted to get loose. You know yourself it's bad enough
when you have a kind master and plenty of coaxing, but there was nothing of that
sort for me. “There was one— —the old master, Mr. Ryder— —who, I think, could soon have
brought me round, and could have done anything with me; but he had given up all
the hard part of the trade to his son and to another experienced man, and he
only came at times to oversee. His son was a strong, tall, bold
man; they called him Samson, and he used to boast that he had never found a horse
that could throw him. There was no gentleness in him, as there was in his
father, but only hardness, a hard voice, a hard eye, a hard hand; and I felt from the
first that what he wanted was to wear all the spirit out of me, and just make
me into a quiet, humble, obedient piece of horse flesh horse flesh Yes, that is all
he thought about,” and Ginger stamped her foot as if the very thought of him made her
angry. Then she went on: “If I did not do exactly what he wanted he would get put
out, and make me run round with that long rain in the training field till he had
tired me out. I think he drank a good deal, and I'm quite sure that the oftener
he drank the worse it was for me. One day
he had worked me hard in every way he could, and when I lay down I was tired,
and miserable, and angry; it all seemed so hard.
The next morning he came for me early, and ran me around again for a long time.
I had scarcely an hour's rest, when he came again for me with a saddle and
bridle and a new kind of bit. I could never quite tell how it came
about; he had only just mounted me on the training ground, when something I did put
him out of temper, and he chucked me hard with the rain The new bit was very
painful, and I reared up suddenly, which angered him still more, and he began to flog me.
I felt my whole spirit set against him, and I began to kick, and plunge, and rear
as I had never done before, and we had a regular fight; for a long time he stuck
to the saddle and punished me cruy with his whip and spurs, but my blood was
thoroughly up, and I cared for nothing he could do if only I could get him
off. At last after a terrible struggle I threw him off backward. I heard him fall
heavily on the turf, and without looking behind me me I galloped off to the other
end of the field; there I turned around and saw my persecutor slowly rising from the ground
and going into the stable. I stood under an oak tree and
watched, but no one came to catch me. The time went on, and the sun was very hot;
the flies swarmed around me and settled on my bleeding flanks where the spurs
had dug in. I felt hungry, for I had not eaten since the early morning, but there
was not enough grass in that meadow for a goose to live on.
I wanted to lie down and rest, but with the saddle strapped tightly on there was
no comfort, and there was not a drop of water to
drink. The afternoon wore on, and the sun got low. I saw the other colts led in, and
I knew they were having a good feed. “At last, just as the sun went down, I
saw the old master come out with a si in his hand. He was a very fine old
gentleman with quite white hair, but his voice was what I should know him by
among a thousand. It was not high, nor yet low, but full, and clear, and kind, and when
he gave orders it was so steady and decided that everyone knew, both horses
and men, that he expected to be obeyed. He came quietly along, now and
then shaking the oats about that he had in the C and speaking cheerfully and
gently to me: 'Come along, lassie, come along, lassie; come along, come
along.' I stood Still still and let him come up; he held the oats to me, and I
began to eat without fear; his voice took all my fear away. He stood by, patting and
stroking me while I was eating, and seeing the clots of blood on my side he
seemed very vexed. 'Poor lassie! it was a bad business, a bad
business;' then he quietly took the rain and led me to the stable; just at the
door stood Samson. I laid my ears back and snapped at him.
'Stand back,' said the master, 'and keep out of her way; you've done a bad day's work
for this Philly He growled out something about a vicious brute H ye,' said the father, 'a
bad-tempered man will never make a good-tempered horse. You've not learned your trade yet,
Samson.' Then he led me into my box, took off the saddle and bridle with his own
hands, and tied me up; then he called for a pale of warm water and a sponge, took
off his coat, and while the stable man held the pale he sponged my sides a good
while, so tenderly that I was sure he knew how bruised and sore they were wo
my pretty one,' he said, 'stand still, stand still.' His very voice did me good, and the
bathing was very comfortable. The skin was so broken at
the corners of my mouth that I could not eat the hay, the stalks hurt me. He looked
closely at it, shook his head, and told the man to fetch a good Brown mash and
put some meal into it. How good that mash was! and so soft and healing to my mouth.
He stood by all the time I was eating, stroking me and talking to the man. 'If a
high metal creature like this,' said he, 'can't be broken by fair means, she will
never be good for anything.' “After that he often came to see
me, and when my mouth was healed the other breaker, Job, they called him, went
on training me; he was steady and thoughtful, and I soon learned what he wanted end of chapter